see it. There we go. There you are. All right, everybody wave high to Robert.
Okay. Awesome. Awesome. So, you ready to get started, Robert? You ready for this man? You
excited? Awesome. Awesome. Awesome. I'm interested to see who's joining us in the chat today.
I see Zoro. I see Joey, Picks, Mindy, Nicholas, Tray, Erica. We have some really great people
here. And I hope you guys are excited because tonight we're going to be doing something
really special. So, tonight, as I said, we're going to be unlocking the secrets to social
mastery to allow you to discover how to read people at a higher level. And I want to open up with
our first question and we're going to bounce this over to you, Robert. Why is it so important
for us to understand the subject matter that we're going to be talking about today?
Well, thank you for having me burning and thank you to everybody out there. I'm kind of
humble to see all these names from all these different places. It's pretty amazing.
Anyway, the reason I did this master class for mentor show is because from all my experience,
all of us humans, we suffer. We have pain in our lives. We have anxiety. We have tension.
We feel frustrated. But we often don't realize the source of our problems, the source of this
tension and the same anxiety and this pain. And I maintain that as a social animal, a lot of our
problems stem from the fact that we really, really don't truly understand the people around us.
You could be married to the same person for 10, 20 years. And there's still things about them
that you don't understand. People are a mystery. They wear masks. They learn very early age.
How to hide certain things that they don't want other people to see. And so, I say let's
imagine, for instance, that you could see into the person that you're dealing with, you had
100% clarity about them. You could see them and understand them perfectly. Now, that is an
ideal and that is basically impossible. But that if we say that's like at 100%,
most of us are understanding of people is more in the area of four or five percent. We're very
self absorbed. We're locked in our phones. We're thinking of our own problems. We're not really
deeply engaging with people. We're not really looking at them. We're not really observing them.
And the point of the master class that I did the mentor show is to be it, to give you the
power to raise that up to 20, 30, 40, 50%. So you have the power to move people in the direction you
want. So that you don't say things that inadvertently insult people and cause all kinds of tensions
and problems that you don't inadvertently get yourself fired for doing things that are socially
awkward, etc. So that you realize that being a social animal is a skill and you raise that
skill to a high enough level where you don't have all of this drama in here. You don't have all of
this tension and you can focus on things that are actually truly important. So that is the point
of this master class that I created and of the mentor show and of what we're talking about today.
Awesome. Thank you so much Robert for sharing that. I just want to jump back to the presentation here.
And I want to share with you guys what we're going to be covering today as the agenda. So here's
what we're going to talk about and what you can expect. We're going to talk about how to see
through the mass people where we're going to talk about how to deal with toxic people. We're also
going to be talking about how to seduce an influence anyone, which is really cool. And this is probably
the most, I think this is what's got me most excited Robert. Is that you're going to be doing
a live Q&A with us here and that's just powerful man. Okay. I'm ready. Awesome. Okay. Cool. So a
couple of things housekeeping before we get into the content for the people who don't know what
mentor show is. Maybe you've never heard about us. We are a platform that has 30 plus master classes
by world leading experts. We offer courses that are really just life changing. Right. So every course
comes with like 10 to 15 lessons and they're super easy to follow. And we give you the opportunity
to tackle subjects like dealing with trauma, gaining confidence, managing your emotions and overcoming
challenges to improve your life. So we give you one click access to this wisdom from experts
who have some of the greatest knowledge in the world, people like Robert Green, but also
people like Gabore Moté, World Renown experts. And you can also get this information down
loaded directly to your desktop, your mobile phone, basically anywhere that you guys want to access.
So if you want to learn more, you can click the link in the comments or you can go to mentor show.com
slash EN and yeah, that's where you can find out more about what we do. So Robert, now that we got
the housekeeping out of the way, let's talk about part one. Let's just really go into this and
talk about how to see through the mass. So I'm going to pop you up over here again and I'm going
to start with this question, Robert. Like what advice would you give someone who really wants to
understand people for who they really are, what they're really like? Well, the first step and the
most important one is to realize that you don't really understand people that you're misleading them.
And the thing that you tend to do is you tend to project your own emotions onto them. You tend to see
them through the lens of your own desires. You want you whether you like them or whether you don't like them.
And things that haven't in the past, your parents, your past relationships, all of the troubles
that you've had in life. And so when you're looking at this person that you're dealing with in your work,
in your relationships, even your children, you're projecting onto them, these images that are inside
your own head that have nothing to do with the reality. So the first step is to tell yourself,
I don't really understand this person that I'm dealing with. They are a meh, to me. So you want
to wipe the sleep clean and you want to try and observe them, but you have to be able to calm
all of your emotional responses down, even your desires to like a person. You have to stop that
and you have to try and find a neutral position where you're just observing them for who they are,
they have their own life, their own dreams, their own crumbs, their own faults. And you want to be
able to see them and you want to have access to them. The second thing you understand is that you
tend to judge people based on their appearances, how they look to you, what they say, you tend to
focus so much on their words, right? But we all know that words can be very slippery. People can say
whatever they want to say. They can say, I love your screenplay. I think your ideas are brilliant,
but they don't mean it at all. Anybody can say what they want. And so you tend to value the appearance
as you tend to value what you see and how people look, how people look and how they appear.
And this can be very tricky and very deceptive. So the most important thing that you can do is to
realize that the appearance, the surface, the faces that you see are not the reality.
Or hiding something. And so your task as a social being, as a social animal, trying to improve
your level of skill is to see past those appearances, see past those masks that people wear. And
one of the things you have to realize is that people have a character. They have something deep inside
that motivates them that makes them do the things that they do. And this character is in things
that they can't even control. It has to do with genetics, it has to do with their early childhood,
it has to do with things that are not visible to you. Right? So you want to judge them. And so
one thing that happens is when people are in stressful situations, for instance, that mask tends
to come off. And you see some of the true person behind that. How they handle stress,
reveals something about what's going on.
.
They're often hiding the exact opposite. They've developed from childhood, they desire to
hide the fact that they're actually very shy, they're very timid, they're very insecure.
And so they put on this front of being super confident. And actually the truth is the opposite.
So you want to be able to see these very overt traits that people have in realize that that is a mask
that happen are how to when people are given power, how do they handle that power?
Suddenly they become very mean-spirited, very cruel to other people. That's revealing who they
are behind the mask. As they're rising up in the company or wherever, they tend to be the court
chair, they be smiling and be friendly. And then as soon as they reach a position of power, that mask
comes off. And they reveal that they're actually somebody very different. The other thing you want to
see, which will reveal about people, who they are truly, is criticizing them. How do they take criticism?
A lot of people can't take criticism on any level. And you certainly don't want to ever hire people
or be in a relationship with people who cannot take any kind of criticism. That reveals
deep, deep levels of insecurity and anxiety. And so, but they're hiding it in some way. And so that
mask comes off when you criticize them. And they be taking things everything so personally. I know
when I was working, when I hire a systems, I often give them a test. And I try and criticize
that a work on some level and say, I don't do it meanly, I don't do it harshly, I do it gently, but I say,
you know, this is something that you're doing that's wrong. And how they respond to that reveals
to me, who they really are. They're trying to pretend they're something. They're trying to pretend
that they're very efficient that they love me, et cetera. But when I criticize them,
that mask tends to come off. So, these are some of the ways you can probe and test who people really are.
And in the master class that I did, I have many, many more ideas about how to pierce and see
behind these masks that people have. Yeah, that's, that's a super powerful one. I think that
anybody, by a show of hand, just by dropping guesses in the chat, like, have you guys
experience some of that, right? Like, have you seen how people respond, like, maybe a boss at work
or a colleague, as they're rising up the ranks, you know, they treat people better, you know,
like things like that, does anybody relate to that just by raising your hand? Because I know I can
rather than that's one of the things that stuck out to me. I would like to also kind of,
shift gears a little bit. And I think this is a good time to move into our next topic,
unless there's anything else that you wanted to cover there. But I'm just curious in the chat also,
like, when we're dealing with people in the world a lot of times, we come across these people that
may not be good people, right? Like, I think you define them as like toxic personalities, and that's what
we've defined them in society. Like, so I'd like to transition to, to that piece.
I mean, just jump back over here to the presentation because I think this is pretty powerful. And this is
this is where part two will come in ladies and gentlemen, and how to deal with these people,
because we're coming in contact with these people on a regular basis, Robert, and I think it would
be really helpful for the people in the audience to understand, you know, how to deal with them,
which brings me to my next question because in the master class, I know you talk about, just,
you talk about dealing with toxic personalities. So how do we recognize these types of people
in our everyday situations? Well, I have a very simple way of reading whether people are truly
toxic. Now, there's, let's say that there are toxic narcissists out there. We all have narcissistic
tendencies where all self-absorbed, but some people are toxic narcissists. There are people who
have toxic envy. We're all subject to feeling envy, but there's some people who carry to
it toxic level. Passive aggression is something we share, but there are people out there who are
toxicly passive aggressive. And the way that recognize them is simple, they tend to occupy
a lot of mental space in your head, thinking about them. They're churning up all of these emotions,
and most of these emotions are negative, fear, anxiety, resentment, frustration, confusion,
guilt. Occasionally, there might be a positive emotion put in there because sometimes these people
are good at playing push-and-plull games where they inject a little bit of affection to get you hooked,
then they pull back. But overall, you can recognize them by the fact that most of the emotions
they turn up are negative, and they absorb so much of your mental space so that when they're not
around when you're not dealing with them, you're thinking about them. And I compare the mind to
like a house. You've invited these people into your house and they won't leave. They're in your
bedroom, they're in your living room. They just take in residents, they're in your can't get rid of them.
Okay? So they're occupying your brain when you don't want them to. That's how you recognize
any kind of talks of person. But the most important thing for you to understand is
they're playing games to get you emotionally involved to trigger you, to get inside if you
to get you, to get their hooks in you. The best thing you can do is to recognize them
before they are able to do that, before they enter your house and take residents in your head.
If you can do that, then you can control your emotions. You can get rid of them, or you can
not have a relation with ship with them, or you can be relatively objective and unemotional in
dealing with them. But once they have their hooks in you, once that toxic narcissist has been
able to get inside of your life and get all these little dramas going on, it's very, very
difficult to disconnect. So the most important thing is to recognize them. And in the master class,
I give you some clues as to, for example, how do it see those toxic narcissists in our life?
I mean, I could talk about all the other types, but just to focus on the toxic narcissist,
which is the main type that we deal with, particularly in the world today. And the thing you must
understand is that a lot of toxic narcissists can rise to positions of power. And why is that?
Because you would think that because they're so self-absorbed, they would never be able to become
like a CEO. But people like Elon Musk and I'm not judging him as as a business person,
but he is very, very narcissistic and he's very, very powerful. The reason is these types of people
from early on in life have learned how to be very charming, how to be very dramatic. They're very
theatrical types of people. And you look at the surfaces I said earlier on, you get too much
wrapped up in people's appearance. They look dramatic. They look exciting. They look confident.
And then you get involved with them. You work for them. You have a relationship with them. And
slowly, you realize that they don't care at all about you. They're simply using you as a pond.
So some of the signs of a toxic narcissist is that they're as they're very theatrical. The other
sign is if you do something, if you insult them in some way, or if you say if you resist them in
some way, they go into what's called toxic rage. They cannot handle any kind of criticism because
they have this deep insecurity and emptiness inside. And so if you trigger any kind of negative
feeling on their part, they will explode into this rage. The other thing I tell people is we didn't
talk about non-verbal communication. And in the mentor class, the mentor show that I do, I focus a lot
a non-verbal communication because it's extremely revealing about people and about who they are.
And toxic narcissists, I, in my experience, have this one very common trait, which is when they're
looking at you, they appear to be interested in excited, but you'll notice that their eyes are kind
of dead. They're not really excited. They're not really interested in you. People who are interested
in you who like you, who love you, who want to be involved with you, who are not using you. Their
faces animated when they look at you, their eyes are open. But when you look at it at a toxic narcissist,
and I've noticed this time again, is their eyes kind of blank, it's kind of dead. They may smile,
but they're not really looking at you. They're looking at you as an object that they can use
for their own purposes. And so these are some of the powerful ways, but the most important thing
is to not get involved with these people, learn the basics of recognizing
envies, people, enviers tend to be among your friends. So one way of seeing a person who's got toxic
envies, they're in a rush to befriends you. You meet them and then three days later, they're
your best friend. They want to know everything about you. They're texting you all the time.
They love you. They think you're great. Now that's not a normal human pattern of behavior.
Most of us are kind of a little bit tentative when we first meet somebody. This is a classic sign of
somebody who's getting close to you in order to hurt you in order because they envy you in some way.
So in the class, I have many, many other more tips about how to recognize these people. So you
don't let them into your house before it's too late. Yeah, I was reflecting on it because I've
gone through the masterclass and I feel like you did an amazing job with identifying those people
because we're going to come up against them in a lot of times. We just can't avoid them.
We're going to come, we can't avoid not coming in contact with them, but this gives us a nice
framework to just figure out who they are and run in the other direction.
So I'm curious for the people in the audience, is there anyone who wants to learn how to build
better relationships, wants to learn how to influence people? Because I think this is a,
and just to kind of conclude Robert, I think from here, what I'm here and you say is like
recognize that the narcissist, they're, the root of how they grew up and they're upbringing
has taught them this way of manipulating people and they're, when they hook into you, you know,
they basically can, that's when they latch into you and they suck you dry and then the person who
envies you, they're trying to get close to you so they can manipulate you and do all that stuff.
Am I on the right track? Yes, we are. And the thing is, talks people,
don't wear a little sign on their head saying, I'm toxic. They've learned very early age to
hide it, to hide it behind of the near, of being charming, of being friendly, of being likable,
etc. And so it's very, very tricky because you can't recognize them, you can't find see them
just based on how they look at you based on their appearances. You have to be able to look
behind them and see the reality. Yeah, totally. So I want to go to our next segment here and part
three of this is how to seduce and influence anyone. And this is, I think this is pretty powerful because
you know, and I'd like to get your take on this because I think when people hear seduction,
they kind of like think of it as like a sexual thing or trying to coerce. But I know that you
there's more to this, right? And I'd like to dig into that. But this is part three. So we'll dive into
this. And let me just go back here to get you on the screen. But like let's talk about this, Robert.
So how can seduction and influence be used to get what we want? And how can people think about this
in a different way than it just being like this thing related to like sexual stuff? Well,
it is some of seduction is definitely sexual and I don't want to deny that. And I talked about that
a little bit in the mentor's class show. I mean, there are people we are situations where we do want
to seduce a man or a woman. So I don't want to run away from that. Sure. But seduction is much
larger than that. And the issue really is how to influence people, how to persuade them. You can't
get through this life. If you don't have the ability to somehow get people on your side to move
them to like your ideas, to want to move in your direction, to not hurt your harm you. And you
have to understand that people are naturally resistant to anything that you want from them.
They're even naturally resistant, obviously, in any kind of sexual seduction. And the whole
game is to lower their resistances, right? And people, particularly in the world today, I hate to judge,
are actually not very good at this. The main thing that you want to be able to be a better
seduce or to be a better influence or in life is the power to get outside of yourself. We are so
self absorbed and to the degree that you enter into the world, the mindset of that other person.
You get inside their skin, you understand their values, you understand how they think. And what they
want, you will have much greater power to move them in the direction that you want. You will be
able to lower their resistances. So I talk in the class about having deep levels of empathy,
where you actually enter their world completely and you understand where they're coming from.
And what their childhood was like and what were the traumas in their life, etc.
Creating that connection of deep levels of empathy will make the other person fall under your
spell and will create a very deep connection between you. The other thing I talk about is how to
validate their egos. We go through life and nobody. We think of ourselves as great usually,
we do unless we have very little empathy. Wow, I'm just a wonderful person. I'm so smart,
I have the best values, you know, on and on and on. But the true validation that we really create
comes from other people, other people telling us, yes, Robert, you are actually smart. Yes,
you are actually a good person. That is the validation people crave. You need to be able to give them
that validation to show them that you think that they are actually a really good person,
that they're even smarter than you are. Right? One of the laws of power and the 48 laws of power is
a pure, dumber than others, you know, and the idea that you're insulting people's intelligence
is incredibly dangerous and incredibly anti-seduction. So you want to validate people in the things
that matter most to them in their egos. And then you want to realize that how you look at people,
how your attitude is towards them, how you think about them, has an infecting power. If you go
up to somebody in a party or any kind of event like that and you're already thinking negative
thoughts about them or you're not insecure, they pick that up, they sense it, and they respond to
you in a defensive negative way. And I want to train you to go up to people even those that you
don't like and just tell yourself, actually I like you, actually I think you're an interesting
person. You don't say any of that, you just think it. You're attitude infects them with a particular
quality and it opens them up to you. So it's a very powerful technique. And finally, there comes
seduction and seduction is basically the ability to give people pleasure in life. None of us
in the world today because we're so politically correct because we're so tight in our bodies.
We don't have enough pleasure. We don't have enough adventure. We're actually craving seduction.
People may not say that, they may say, oh seduction is evil. Or Robert Green is evil.
Oh, the art of seduction is a bad book. But secretly, they want it, they crave it because all of us
want to be taken out of ourselves. We want to be taken on the adventure. And so you have to be able,
so you have to understand that that is the power that you have. But what I talk about in that
and that particular segment is if you two obvious, if it's too clear that you're trying to
seduce people, if you two cold and manipulative, they can sense it. So you have to disguise yourself.
You have to peer natural. It can bake. It has to actually be something, but everybody has seductive
qualities. And so the idea is you want to be a seduce or in life. And you want to be able to seduce
people even in the office, whether it's an absolutely no sexual element to them. But the sense
that you're a charming person, that you like them, and that you are to know you,
is going to be an exciting adventure that there's some mystery about you being a seduction.
It involves a lot of creating mystery. It's very, very powerful. So just imagine if this way,
you're dealing with people on all levels and you're lowering their resistance, you're lowering
their defensiveness. They have walls and you're breaking through those walls and they're falling
under your spell. And that's what I'm discussing in that part of the mentor show and go into great
depth. Yeah. And this is super powerful for me, Robert, because being an entrepreneur,
you have to go out and you have to sell. So part of, I look at the seduction as the stuff that I've
learned from you, I look at me seducing someone is like, that's making the sale. It's getting them
to buy into my ideas and to even want a sales call. I'm going in and I have to lower their resistance.
Right. So that to me, that's how I think about seduction. Would you say that's in line?
Yes, very much. So just think of it this way. To the degree that you enter into their world,
that you think of their needs, their interests, their desires, you become a much better sales person
on any level. And whether it's in personal relationships or whatever. But the worst kind of sales
mirror those that have their own kind of speel in their head and they're thinking about how great
their product is and they're trying to sell it to you. And you're just like, man, I don't
I don't want to hear you tune them out because we hear so many people trying to sell those things.
But if they think it through and they go, this is an individual I'm dealing with.
This is some of their needs, their world, their problems. I'm going to appeal to their self-interest.
I'm going to appeal to what they need in life. Suddenly, doors open up. I know personally,
for instance, in my own life, I never, ever have enough time. I'm so busy and it drives me crazy.
If somebody entered my life, somehow promising the prospect of saving me time, I would melt in front
of them. The way it's to sell me, whatever it is, right? But people come to me and they don't think
that that's, you know, I get requests all of the time where people want to be my apprentice,
it's said, you know, any kind of function with me or partner with me, they don't think of that.
They don't realize how busy I am, but everybody is super busy. So being able to pierce inside the
world of the other person to go, what is their need? Not my need, what is their need? What are their
secret desires? That is the secret to any kind of sale or any kind of seduction.
Love it. Powerful. I think speaking of these, I think this is a perfect time to transition to talk
about the master class and how it could help our audience here at a deeper level. And
in everyone, I'm acknowledging, I want to acknowledge that I see a lot of questions in the chat and
make sure you guys keep putting those in the chat. We're going to feel those at the end. For those of
you who didn't hear at the beginning, Robert's going to stick around and do a Q&A. So you'll
guys will want to make sure you stay to the very end. So put all those questions there. Quick
question for you, Robert. I know we talked about a lot and we're covering a lot here. And, you know,
there's probably people that want to go deeper, right? If people want this stuff to sink in,
how can your master class really help us get to the root and really make this a practice for us?
Well, a lot of what's in this master class is based on the laws of human nature,
which you've you delved into, it is a 580 page book. It's very dense. Okay, I have tried to
simplify it on some level and give you the basic ideas that are contained in that book.
Very concentrated. It's like a straight shot of whiskey that I'm giving you. There's no one.
Ice, it's just the whiskey. So you're getting the straight material right there. And I'm trying
to make it very practical. It's not abstract. It's not me intellectualizing and going on and on about
psychology. It's about your life, the problems that you're dealing with. And so I'm trying to train
you in this art of dealing with people on a higher level. I have exercises, which is something that I didn't
have in laws of human nature. I worked very, very hard to put this mentor show together. I put a
lot of thought in it. And I thought of exercises that can help you realize these ideas in your own life.
You know, how to observe people in your everyday life exercise about that, how to control your
emotions so that talks that people don't get under your skin, how to alter the people that you're
dealing with through your attitude, through how you think of them on and on. So these exercises are
very focused. It's a very focused mentor, class, ship, class on how to understand people and deal
with them in great detail. Okay. So there's not a lot of abstract stuff. There are stories in there,
but the stories are a lot of it for my own life or from a couple of stories in the laws of human
nature, but they're very direct and they're very applicable and they're very relevant. So it's a
extremely practical show. I personally believe that combined with the laws of human nature,
reading the book and doing the master class, it will really benefit the most. But that is the idea
behind my what I craft for this. Beautiful. Man, I'm going to need the help of everybody in the audience
today. I want you guys to get super hyped for this one because we have something amazingly special
for you guys today. So just by show a hand in the chat right now, I want you guys to tell me
who wants to discover Robert Green's method for gaining power to see people as they are. Drop
a meet in the chat right now. Light it up, light it up. Let me see who's ready for this because this
is going to be phenomenal guys. Let me see show some love in the chat. Oh, I see it. I see you guys
coming in. I'm seeing some mees. I'm seeing John, Rand Taylor, France, Francesca, Mindy, Javon,
Palma, so many people. Okay, okay, I think you guys are ready for it. I won't hold it back. I won't hold
it back. So without further ado, it's my pleasure to introduce you guys to Robert Green's
exclusive master class, social mastery, the power of seeing people just as they
are. Robert, I know you talked a lot about why, what this master class is about,
can you just share any more insight on into why you decided to do it now and that this time
versus like any other time in history or what makes it a now thing, what makes it so urgent?
Well, people are progressively getting worse at it and I don't mean to be so judgmental
because I know it, something that's affected me, but also I look at the emails that I receive
people wanting advice. It's also based on my consulting work with people who are very powerful and
very successful and I've noticed that in the world today, people are progressively getting worse
and worse and worse in their social relationships, in their interactions. They are mistreating
people, they are saying the wrong things, they are not getting, they're not interesting people
in their own ideas and it's because we've become increasingly self absorbed in this world.
We are too virtual, we're too wrapped up in our phones and being social is a skill.
If you think about like a skill like shooting baskets, free throws or whatever, a three-point shot,
if you do a thousand, just ten thousand shots, you'll get better at it.
Well, being social, the skill is interacting with people, interacting with them in bars, going to
markets and interacting with people, interacting with strangers in your office or on the street or whatever,
over and over and over again. And that develops the skill, it develops and finds to sense the
activity to other people. And it's like a great way that we have in our in our spirit.
And the more we practice it, the more we become sensitive to other people to their moods,
to their non-verbal behavior. But we are growing in sensitive, we're growing the opposite direction.
And I'm very worried about it. So that's why I wrote the Laws of Human Nature.
And that's why I crafted this masterclass to help you get out of the shell that we're all
retreating into because of all of the technology around us.
Yeah, I love that man. It's we're living in some interesting times. And I think it's time for us
to take accountability and for our growth. And that's why I love what we've got cooking here.
So you guys have heard since the beginning of the webinar, this is only the tip of the iceberg.
So let me just dive in and give you guys a sneak peek here. We have tons of,
if we have tons of value here, this is lesson number one, this is understanding the laws of human
nature. So there's going to be, I think there's six lessons in here that are combined.
These are the trainings that Robert has done. We're going to be covering everything in there
from non-verbal communication that was something that you talked about earlier, Robert, you